Shichao Xu

Ph.D. Candidate
Department of Computer Science
Northwestern University
Tech Room L476, 2145 Sheridan Road
Evanston, IL 60208, United States

OBJECTIVE

I am at my fourth year as a Ph.D. candidate and aiming at finding a full-time research intern/job position.

E-mail: shichaoxu2023@u.northwestern.edu

Homepage: https://shichao.netlify.app

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/shichao-xu-6a0584214

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Machine learning, Deep learning, Cyber-physical system, Learning from imperfect data

SUMMARY

I am a fourth-year Ph.D. candidate in the Computer Science Department at Northwestern University, and my advisor is Prof Qi Zhu. I also work collaboratively with Prof. Xiao Wang, Prof. Zhaoran Wang from Northwestern University, Prof. Yanzhi Wang from Northeastern University, Prof. Zheng O'Neill from Texas A&M University. I received my undergraduate degree from Shanghai Jiao Tong University (ACM Honors Class) in 2018. Previously, I was a research intern in visual computing group at MSRA, under the supervision of Jifeng Dai. I also worked as a research assistant at SJTU BCMI Lab, directed by Professor Liqing Zhang.

My research interests lie in the field of Artificial Intelligence and Cyber-Physical System, especially with the topic of learning from imperfect data. While deep learning is more and more frequently included as a component of a large complex system with various factors included, many challenges are exposed in actual development and integration. Instead of simply considering AI as a stand-alone software application, we should take more issues into account – data availability and quality, disturbance and attacks, generalization and adaptation, etc. Currently, I am focusing on the challenge of learning from imperfect data and one of our latest work Weak Adaptation Learning is accepted by ICCV 2021. And we also develop a containerized framework for building control, which makes the study of RL on this complex system much easier. Our next step is focus on the challenge of sample efficiency in RL on real-world application.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Northwestern University	IL, USA
Ph.D. in Computer Science	09/2018-present
Master's degree in Computer Science (GPA: 3.9/4.0)	09/2018-06/2021
Cornell University	NY, USA
Summer School	06/2017-07/2017
ACM Class, Zhiyuan College, Shanghai Jiao Tong University	Shanghai, China
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (GPA 3.9/4.3)	09/2014-07/2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Northwestern University
Research Assistant in IDEAS Lab
09/2018-present

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Research Assistant in Center for Brain-like Computing and Machine Intelligence

Microsoft Research Asia

Research Intern in Visual Computing Group

Shanghai, China 09/2014-07/2018 **Beijing, China** 08/2017-01/2018

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Our latest work about Containerized Framework for Building Control is under review!
- Lixu Wang*, Shichao Xu*, Ruiqi Xu, Xiao Wang, and Qi Zhu. "Non-Transferable Learning: A New Approach for Model Verification and Authorization." [link] (latest!)
- Shichao Xu, Yangyang Fu, Yixuan Wang, Zheng O'Neill, and Qi Zhu. "Model-assisted Learning-based Framework for Sensor Fault-Tolerant Building HVAC Control." The 8th ACM International Conference on Systems for Energy-Efficient Buildings, Cities, and Transportation (BuildSys '21), 2021, Coimbra, Portugal (acceptance ratio = 26%)
- Shichao Xu*, Lixu Wang*, Yixuan Wang, and Qi Zhu. "Weak Adaptation Learning--Addressing Cross-domain Data Insufficiency with Weak Annotator." IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2021.
- Lixu Wang, Shichao Xu, Xiao Wang, and Qi Zhu. "Towards Class Imbalance in Federated Learning." In 35th
 Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), A Virtual Conference, 2021.
- Qi Zhu, Chao Huang, Ruochen Jiao, Shuyue Lan, Hengyi Liang, Xiangguo Liu, Yixuan Wang, Zhilu Wang, Shichao Xu "Safety-Assured Design and Adaptation of Learning-Enabled Autonomous Systems." Proceedings of the 26th Asia and South Pacific Design Automation Conference (ASP-DAC). 2021.
- Yixuan Wang, Chao Huang, Zhilu Wang, Shichao Xu, Zhaoran Wang, Qi Zhu. "Cocktail: Learn a Better Neural Network Controller from Multiple Experts via Adaptive Mixing and Robust Distillation" 2021 58th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), Virtual Conference, 2021.
- Rumia Masburah, Rajib Lochan Jana, Ainuddin Khan, Shichao Xu, Shuyue Lan, Soumyajit Dey, Qi Zhu, "Adaptive Learning Based Building Load Prediction for Microgrid Economic Dispatch" Design, Automation & Test in Europe Conference & Exhibition (DATE), 2021
- Shichao Xu, Yixuan Wang, Yanzhi Wang, Zheng O'Neill, and Qi Zhu. "One for Many: Transfer Learning for Building HVAC Control." In Proceedings of the 7th ACM International Conference on Systems for Energy-Efficient Buildings, Cities, and Transportation, (BuildSys '20), 2020.
- Shichao Xu, Shuyue Lan, and Zhu Qi, "MaskPlus: Improving Mask Generation for Instance Segmentation" The IEEE
 Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision. 2020
- Chao Huang, Shichao Xu, Zhilu Wang, Shuyue Lan, Wenchao Li, and Qi Zhu. "Opportunistic Intermittent Control with Safety Guarantees for Autonomous Systems," 2020 57th ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), San Francisco, CA, USA, 2020, pp. 1-6

PROJECT

DoE Project: <u>Securing Grid-interactive Efficient Buildings (GEB) through Cyber Defense and</u>
 <u>Resilient System (CYDRES).</u>

AWARDS

•	Northwestern University Ph.D. Fellowship	2018-2019
•	Zhiyuan College honor scholarship	2014-2018
•	Excellent students' scholarship, Shanghai Jiao Tong University	2014-2018
•	Bronze medal in National Olympiad in Informatics	2013
	Gold medal in National Olympiad in Informatics in Provinces	2012